Mannes - Damrosch Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Writings, 1876-1956 and undated, bulk 1946-56 (Box 3-4)
  - Mannes, Marya
    - Barcelona story [The other side], n.d. (Box-folder 3/24)
    - The best of Marya Mannes, 1986 [book] (Box-folder 3/25)
    - The Boltons plan a party, n.d. [script] (Box-folder 3/26)
    - Children in trouble, 1955 Sept. 22 (Box-folder 3/27)
    - Coming of age: Report on the Hodson Center, 1954 Dec. 16 (Box-folder 3/28)
    - The day off, n.d. (Box-folder 3/29)
    - The domesticated male, [?] Jun. 23 (Box-folder 3/30)
    - Free enterprise, n.d. (Box-folder 3/31)
    - Happy new year: or, the worst winter of all, 1946 Jan. (Box-folder 3/32)
    - Health bar, n.d. (Box-folder 3/33)
    - A high standard of giving, n.d. (Box-folder 3/34)
    - [Juvenalia], 1912-20, n.d. (Box-folder 3/35)
    - Leopold Damrosch Mannes, 1964 Aug. 15 [funeral speech] (Box-folder 3/36)
    - Letter from Italy, 1946 July (Box-folder 3/37)
    - Letter from Lisbon, [?] June 25 (Box-folder 3/38)
    - Letter from "Prosa" (Italy), 1948 Mar. (Box-folder 3/39)
    - A mirror for his love [Please look at me], 1949 May (Box-folder 3/40)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box-folder 3/41)
    - 'Nessfeness' at Harvard, 1956 May 31 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - One hundred and four make one: The Philharmonic Symphony Orchestra, Part I, Part II (incomplete), n.d. (Box-folder 4/2)
    - The other side see Barcelona story
    - The P is silent as in 'Yalta', n.d. (Box-folder 4/3)
    - The people vs. McCarthy, 1954 Apr. 27 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Please look at me see A mirror for his love
    - [Poems: A-F], Contents Address book And after Christmas Asian bloc Appease porridge hot Attention U.S. Senate Ballad of gallant ladies (Formerly of Mexico and Egypt) Ballad of John L. (Prompted by his latest gesture to the ILA) Balls and chains Black market Breaking the sound barrier Bus to Harlem Cable from Paris, 1950 Cable to Vogue, 1950 Cairo-practice see Egyptian crisis Carol for our times Christmas list Christmas, 1952 (Clinton, Little Rock, etc.) "The Association for the Advancement of White People" Conquest Contradictums Crooner Cry see Wynken, Blynken, and GOP Dean Dulles Eastland on the judiciary Egyptian crisis 806 mules off to assist NATO Embarrassing moment Emergency End of summer Epitaph Evasion Everest Farewell to Harry Fiddledeedee Filling the vacuum First year away Foreign-policy waltz 'Fullbright fears for student plan' (Box-folder 4/14)
    - [Poems: G-O], Contents The G.O.P. goes South Geneva The ghost fleet The greatest tricks on earth Government agency Guilt Happily Help wanted Highest standard of living yet How nice for mice Identification (The ides of March) '54 or recession If Churchill resigns I'm as liberal as anyone, but— Isolation Japanese fisherman dies Language guide to the liberated The leader Legend [excerpts] Light verse Lincoln to Shivers to Byrnes Lines to an Italian soldier Lines to a Puritan (Truro, Mass) Love in war Masters of Manhattan A matter of health Mediterranean Message to Boris Pasternak Miracle Mirror, mirror, on the wall Negative ("... and they forced the townsmen to bury the victims...") The new class (Hoffa, Faubus, etc.) New country "Nigger-Lovers" Nix, son see The leader No place to kneel Note to writers Nursery rhyme see Appease porridge hot Ode to barbiturates also Ode to barbiturate Odium on an escalator Old proverb On discarding prepared speeches (Oppenheimer) The waiting ones Our position is clear (Box-folder 4/15)
    - [Poems: P-Z], Contents Party man Peace-march Peasants People's republic vs. Public opinion Perfumed note see Identification Perfumes of Arabia Plane shot down Postmaster versus Poet Relaxing world tension Reproach The return (Elections in Italy) Savonarola on Fifth Avenue The senator and 'Bob' Shell shock Silly verse The singular advantages of having no responsibility Six Russian newsmen brave stronghold of capitalism South African lullaby Ship sunk Sonnet Stimulant Stock market 'Stocks spurt after the elections' Strings Tail gunner They were expedient The thrill killers To Americans, 1940 see Emergency To Nelson and Ellen To FDR and HST - 1952 TV report to the nation The unconsulted The untouched Untitled Waste of energy Westerns are more fun Whiffenpoof song (new look): Top U.S. officials discuss security White (House) Christmas Wynken, Blynken and GOP (With apologies to Eugene Field) (Box-folder 4/16)
    - "Poor Richard Club" speech, n.d. (Box-folder 4/5)
    - [Reviews and criticism], 1952-56, n.d. (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Riggs: Where psychiatrists learn, 1954 Nov. 4 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Romulus and Remus, n.d. (Box-folder 4/8)
    - The stepmother, 1951 Oct. (Box-folder 4/9)
    - This is America: Divorce edition II, 1946 Mar. 18 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Togetherness, n.d. (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Unidentified (Box-folder 4/12)
    - What's wrong with the comics?, 1948 Mar. 2 [panel] (Box-folder 4/13)
- Music (Box 8-10, Box 35)
  Music consists of original manuscripts by Leopold Damrosch, manuscripts of compositions arranged or transcribed by Leopold Damrosch, original manuscripts by Edmund Singer, and copyist's manuscripts of other compositions.
  Arranged alphabetically by composer, then by title
  - Arcadelt, Jacob
    - Ave Maria, Transcriber's holograph score; [1] p.; Transcribed by Leopold Damrosch (Box-folder 8/1)
  - Berlioz, Hector
    - La captive, [op. 12], Transcriber's holograph score; [2] p.; Transcribed by Leopold Damrosch (Box-folder 8/2)
  - Damrosch, Leopold
    - Cherry ripe, Holograph vocal parts (Box-folder 8/3)
    - [Children's songs], Holograph piano-vocal scores; Contents: Baby Bo; [1] p. see also Cradle song The boy and the foot; [2] p. see also Night and day Cradle song Copy 1; [2] p. Copy 2; [2] p. On inside: Baby Bo; [2] p. Ding, dong!; [2] p. see also In the wood An Easter carol; [1] p. On verso: Jessie; [1] p. Handel see Little squirrels In the wood; [2] p. On p. 2-3: Ding, dong!; [2] p. On p. 4: Punkydoodle and Tollapin; [1] p. Jamie's on the stormy sea; [5] p. Jessie see An Easter carol see Sabbath morn Joy, hope, love; [1] p. On verso: Unidentified sketch; [1] p. see also Little squirrels The kitchen clock Copy 1; [1] p. Copy 2; [2] p. On p. 1: Music by Bob Thrush Listen, listen see Little squirrels Little squirrels; [4] p. Also on p. 3-4: Handel On p. 5: Punkydoodle and Tollapin; [1] p. Also on p. 5: Listen, listen (Joy, hope, love) A million little diamonds see The trio Night and day Copy 1; [1] p. Copy 2; [1] p. On verso: [The boy and the boot]; [1] p. Punkydoodle and lollapin; [2] p. see also In the wood see also Little squirrels Rain, hail, snow Copy 1: [2] p. Copy 2: [2] p. Sabbath morn; [2] p. On p. 2: Jessie; [1] p. Sewing; [1] p. There's a ship; [4] p. The trio Copy 1; [3] p. On p. 4: A million little diamonds; [1] p. Copy 2; [4] p. A valentine; [2] p. The wren and the hen Copy 1; [3] p. Copy 2; [2] p. (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Concert-Allegro für die Violine, Copyist's ms. piano score; 26 p. (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Concertstück im Charakter einer Serenade, op 9., Copyist's ms. full score; [92] p.; 26 p., [9] p., 17 p., 38 p.; Laid in: holograph full score of second movement; 7 p. (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Zweites concert für Violine, Holograph piano score; [36] p.; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, F# minor (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Zweites concert für Violine, Holograph piano score; [28] p.; Differs from previous manuscript (Box/Folder 10/6); Uniform title: Concerto, violin, F# minor (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Zweites violinconcert (G-dur) mit Orchester, Copyist's ms. violin part; [23] p.; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, G major (Box-folder 8/9)
    - [Faust], Holograph piano sketch; [3] p.; On p. 1: Juni 1879 (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Der fremden Kinder heiliger Christ, Holograph piano-vocal score; [8] p. (Box-folder 8/11)
    - Frisch gesungen!, Holograph full score; [2] p.; Holograph parts; [12] p.; Laid in: cover [2] p. (Box-folder 8/12)
    - Frühlingsahnung, Holograph vocal score; [2] p. (Box-folder 8/13)
    - Hymenäen I-II, Holograph piano score; [10] p. (Box-folder 8/14)
    - König Harald Harfagar, Copyist's ms. piano-vocal score; [10] p. (Box-folder 8/15)
    - Maireigen: Lied für eine Singstimme, Copyist's ms. piano-vocal score; [3] p. (Box-folder 8/16)
    - Mazurka für Violine mit begleiten der Pianoforte, Holograph piano score; [2] p. [version 1] (Box-folder 8/17)
    - Mazurka für Violine mit begleiten der Pianoforte, Holograph piano score; [2] p. [version 2] (Box-folder 8/18)
    - Musik für "Jungfrau von Orleans" von Schiller, Holograph full score; [200] p.; On p. 2: 2/12 [18]56; At end: 31/12 [18]56 (Box-folder 8/19)
    - National ode, Holograph full score; 35 p.; Also known under the title: Centennial ode (Box-folder 8/20)
    - National ode, Holograph vocal score; 11 p.; Also known under the title: Centennial ode (Box-folder 8/21)
    - Octette, Holograph vocal parts; [9] p. (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Orchester-Fantasie für Clavier gesetzt von Carl Tausig, Holograph piano score; [8] p.; In pencil: op. 9 (Box-folder 35/1)
    - Ring out, wild bells, Holograph vocal parts; [8] p. (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Romeo und Julie, Holograph full score; Folders: 10/1: Act I; [66] p. At end: 26 Mai 1864 10/2: Act II; [192] p. On p. 1: 27 Mai 1864 10/3: Act III; [134] p. Laid in: libretto; [6] p. At end: 18 August 1864 10/4: Libretto and notes; [19] p. 10/5: Sketches; [136]p. (Box-folder 10/1-5)
    - Sinfonie, Holograph sketches; [15] p. (Box-folder 35/2)
    - [Sulamith], Holograph full score; [26] p.; Caption title: No. 6 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - [Sulamith], Holograph full score (incomplete); [11] p. (Box-folder 9/4)
    - [Sulamith], Holograph solo vocal parts; [11] p. (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Unidentified, Manuscripts in the hand of Leopold Damrosch; [38] p.; Copyist's ms. parts (incomplete) (Box-folder 9/6-7)
    - Veni creator spiritus, Holograph organ-vocal score; [2] p. (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Wie die Blüthen leise Träumen, Photo-reproduction of holograph piano-vocal score; [1] p.; 3 copies (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Wie die Blüthen leise Träumen, Holograph sketch; [2] p. (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Zehn Lieder aus "Des Knaben Wunderhorn" für eine Singstimme mit Begleitung der Pianoforte, Holograph piano-vocal score; [15] p. (Box-folder 9/11)
  - Field, John
    - Nocturne von Field für Violine mit begl. von kl. Orchester übertrager von Leopold Damrosch, Arranger's holograph full score; [5] p.; Arranged by Leopold Damrosch (Box-folder 9/12)
  - Gottwald, Heinrich
    - Ecce quomodo moritur justus, Copyist's ms. vocal score; [3] p. (Box-folder 9/13)
    - Exaudi nos, Copyist's ms. vocal score; [4] p.
    - Waldlied, op. 18, Copyist's ms. vocal score; [4] p.
  - Handel, George Frideric
    - Chor aus Theodora, Transcriber's holograph score; [1] p.; Transcribed by Leopold Damrosch (Box-folder 9/14)
    - Nasce al bosco [from Ezio], Transcriber's holograph score; [4] p.; Transcribed by Leopold Damrosch
    - Unidentified, Transcriber's holograph part; [1] p.; Transcribed by Leopold Damrosch
  - Mannes, Leopold
    - A birdie song [juvenalia], Holograph piano-vocal score; [4] p. (Box-folder 9/15)
    - [Music, when soft voices die], Reproduction of holograph piano-vocal score; [1] p.; On p. 1: Sept. 12, 1924
    - To be sung, Photocopy of holograph piano-vocal score; [2] p.
    - [Why jadest thou in death], Reproduction of holograph piano-vocal score; [2] p.; On p. 1: Sept. 17, 1924
  - Schubert, Franz
    - Peace, troubled soul, Adapter's holograph close score and solo vocal parts; [5] p.; Adapted by Leopold Damrosch (Box-folder 9/16)
  - Singer, Edmund
    - Air vallaque, Holograph score for violin and piano; [3] p.; On p. 3-5: Wallachisches Lied; Holograph score for violin and piano; [5] p. (Box-folder 9/17)
    - Cadenz zu Beethoven's Violin Concert, Holograph violin part; [3] p. (Box-folder 9/18)
  - Viotti, Giovanni Battista
    - [Unidentified], Ms. score for violin and piano; [5] p. (Box-folder 9/19)
  - Wagner, Richard
    - Rheingold, Copyist's ms. vocal parts in hand of Leopold Damrosch; [3] p. (Box-folder 9/20)
    - Tannhaüser, Leopold Damrosch holograph full score with notes (incomplete); [127] p. (Box-folder 9/21)
- Financial / Legal, 1908-1944 (Box 4)
  Financial papers include miscellaneous items from David and Clara Mannes; Legal papers include passport, contract and report cards.
  Arranged chronologically by date
  - 1908-44, n.d. (Box-folder 4/17)
- Programs, 1876-1947 and undated (Box 4, Box 11, Box 35)
  Printed and typescript programs of music performances, lecture and commencement exercises.
  Arranged alphabetically by organization or event, then chronologically by date.
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science Summer Meeting, 1936 (Box-folder 4/18)
  - David and Clara Mannes sonata recitals, 1908-46, n.d. (Box-folder 11/1)
  - David and Clara Mannes promotional materials, 1895-1914, n.d. (Box-folder 35/3)
  - David Mannes and Leopold Mannes recital, 1935 Apr. 15 (Box-folder 4/19)
  - David Mannes Music School, 1920 (Box-folder 35/4)
  - Grand Opera by the Pappenheim and Adams Company, 1878, n.d. (Box-folder 11/2)
  - Her Majesty's Opera Company, 1880, n.d. (Box-folder 11/3)
  - Leo Godowsky and Leopold Mannes recital and concert, 1935, 1937 (Box-folder 11/4)
  - Leopold Mannes recital / concert, 1938-40 (Box-folder 4/20)
  - Luigi Silva and Leopold Mannes recital, 1941 (Box-folder 4/21)
  - Mannes Quartet, 1900 (Box-folder 4/22)
  - Metropolitan Museum of Art, free concerts, 1947 (Box-folder 4/23)
  - New York Public Library, six free chamber music concerts, n.d. (Box-folder 4/24)
  - Philharmonic Society of New York, 1876-77 (Box-folder 4/25)
  - Rochester Civic Orchestra, 1935 (Box-folder 4/26)
  - A tribute to Marya Mannes, n.d. (Box-folder 4/27)
  - Unidentified, n.d. (Box-folder 4/28)
  - Veltin School Commencement Exercises, 1923 (Box-folder 4/29)
  - Walter Damrosch golden jubilee, 1935 (Box-folder 11/5)
  - WPA Federal Music Project, 1938 (Box-folder 4/30)
- Scrapbooks, 1925-56 (Box 11)
  Handmade 25th wedding anniversary album for Walter and Margaret Damrosch and a scrapbook of clippings, programs, letters, telegrams, a photograph, and a brochure for David Mannes' 90th birthday.
  - Walter and Margaret Damrosch [wedding] anniversary, 1925 (Box-folder 11/6)
  - David Mannes' 90th birthday, 1956 (Box-folder 11/7)
- Clippings, 1881-1951 and undated
  Printed and typescript clippings from magazines and newspapers.
  Arranged alphabetically by person, then chronologically
  - Damrosch, Leopold
    - 1881-1932 (Box-folder 4/31)
    - 1881-1885, 1914 (Box-folder 35/5)
  - Damrosch, Walter, 1933-44 (Box-folder 11/8)
  - Mannes, David and Clara
    - 1913-49, n.d. (Box-folder 4/32)
    - 1913-42 (Box-folder 35/6)
  - Mannes, Leopold
    - 1925-64, n.d. (Box-folder 4/33)
    - 1935-51, n.d. (Box-folder 36/1)
  - Mannes, Marya, 1926-48, n.d. (Box-folder 4/33)
- Photographs (Box 5-6, Box 12-26, Box 34-36)
  The Photographs series is represented by two subseries: Photoprings; Albums. Photoprints consist of black & white positive prints. Albums consist of black & white prints, some color positive prints.
  Arrangement is by subseries, then by alphabetically by subject or chronologically by date
  - Photoprints (Box 5, Box 12, Box 35)
    - Blow, David (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Brandt, Marianne (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Consolo, Anna and Ernesto (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Damrosch, Clara, Elizabeth, and Helene with European travel group (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Damrosch family portraits (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Damrosch, Frank (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Damrosch, Helene von Heimburg (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Damrosch, Leopold (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Damrosch, Walter (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Heimburg, Marie von (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Henschel, George (Box-folder 5/13)
    - Mannes, Clara Damrosch (Box-folder 5/14)
    - Mannes, David (Box-folder 5/18)
    - Mannes, Leopold (Box-folder 5/21)
    - Mannes, Marya (Box-folder 5/24)
    - Mannes family (Box-folder 5/28)
    - Mannes School of Music (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Miscellaneous [buildings, interiors, and scenery] (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Tee Van, Helen Damrosch [wedding] (Box-folder 5/29)
    - Unidentified (Box-folder 5/30)
  - Albums (Box 13-26, Box 36)
    - [#1]: 1898-1900, Paradox Lake...[illegible], Includes Paradox Lake, Whitney's Beach, the Mannes family, the Seymour's home, and Helen Tee Van as a girl (Box 13)
    - [#2]: 1901-02, Seal Harbor, Includes Mannes family at home, baby pictures of Leopold Mannes (Box-folder 6/1)
    - [#3]: 1903, Europe, Includes buildings, mainly in Germany, Belgium and Switzerland (Box 14)
    - [#4]: [1904-06], Includes photographs and text about Marya Mannes as a baby; also, includes a photograph of the Damrosch family memorial and a notice of Helene Damrosch's death which occurred four days after Marya's birth; Inscribed: This book illuminated and given by Elizabeth Mosenthal (Box 15)
    - [#5]: 1905, Mannesden, Lake Champlain, Includes Mannesden, the Mannes' summer home, and the Mannes family (Box-folder 16/1)
    - [#6]: 1905, Includes the Mannes family (Box-folder 16/2)
    - [#7]: 1906, Summer of, second summer at Mannesden, Includes Mannesden, a guest list of visitors, Frank Damrosch holding Marya Mannes, and silhouettes of the Mannes family (Box-folder 17/1)
    - [#8]: 1906-1907 [illegible], Includes Mannesden, Frank Damrosch holding Marya Mannes, and Margaret Damrosch and her daughters (Box 34)
    - [#9]: 1910, [illegible] - 1911, Seal Harbor, Includes Mannes family in Europe [?] and Seal Harbor, and Frank Damrosch (Box 18)
    - [#10]: 1912 [illegible], Includes Mannes family on vacation [to ?] and at home (Box 19)
    - [#11]: 1912, Includes the Mannes family on vacation [to ?] (Box 20)
    - [#12]: 1913, Europe [illegible], Includes the Mannes family in Europe, some with Margaret and Walter Damrosch (Box-folder 17/2)
    - [#13]: 1913, Includes the Mannes family (Box-folder 21/1)
    - [#14]: 1914-15 [illegible], Includes the Mannes family, other children, and a wedding [one of Walter Damrosch's daughters?] (Box 22)
    - [#15]: 1915 - [illegible], Includes the Mannes family on vacation to Washington, DC [and other places?] (Box 23)
    - [#16]: 1919, Summer vacation, Includes the Mannes family on vacation to Montreal and [the American West] (Box-folder 21/2)
    - [#17]: 1930, Summer, David and Clara Mannes' Holidays, Includes Clara, David, and Marya in Europe (Box 24)
    - [#18]: [1931], Includes photographs and travel postcards of the Mannes family on vacation (Box-folder 6/2-3)
    - [#19]: 1938, Museum Concert, Includes David Mannes' activities on the night of one of his free concerts at the Metropolitan Museum of Art; On inside cover: "Photos taken by Leopold [Mannes] at the Metropolitan Museum & 120 E. 75, March 1938, New York" (Box-folder 6/4)
    - [#20]: [1938], Includes some of the same photographs as album #19 above, as well as additional ones of the same concert (Box-folder 6/5)
    - [#21]: [1940-41], Includes David Blow as a baby, Marya Mannes, Richard Blow, and Evelyn and Leopold Mannes (Box-folder 6/6)
    - [#22]: Undated, Includes the Mannes family, Marya as a baby, and house interiors (Box-folder 6/7)
    - [#23]: Undated, Includes the Mannes family, Marya as a young girl, vacations, Frank Damrosch, Frank Damrosch Jr. and one of Frank Jr.'s sons as a baby (Box-folder 25/1)
    - [#24]: Undated, Includes Marya Mannes and Richard Blow in Italy and Greece, Marya's sculpture, travel postcards, and David Blow's christening party with Walter Damrosch attending (Box-folder 25/2)
    - [#25]: Undated, Includes photographs and travel postcards of Havana, Santa Fe and the American Southwest (Box-folder 6/8)
    - [#25]: Harveycar motor cruises through the great Southwest, Map accompanying photograph album #25 (Box-folder 36/2)
    - [#26]: Undated, Loose page from unidentified photo album; includes pictures of Mannes family, ca. 1910? (Box-folder 26/1)
    - [#27]: Undated, Includes buildings and art in Europe (Box-folder 26/2)
- Artwork, 1889-1973 and undated (Box 27-28, Box 30, Box 33, Box 35-36)
  Artwork consists of pencil sketches, ink drawings, pastel drawings, watercolors, engraving and photogravure plates and reproductions of drawings, sketches and sculptures.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject or title, then by medium
  - Cortot, Alfred
    - Pencil sketches, by unidentified artist, n.d. (Box-folder 27/1)
  - Damrosch, Helene
    - Pencil sketch (portrait), by unidentified artist, 1893 Jan. 9 (Box-folder 27/2)
  - Damrosch, Leopold
    - Engraving plate (portrait), by unidentified artist, n.d. (Box-folder 30/3)
    - Pencil sketch (portrait), by Friedrich Preller, 1857 Oct. 7 (Box-folder 27/3)
  - Damrosch, Walter
    - Reproduction of pencil sketch (portrait), by Churchill Ettinger, n.d. (Box-folder 27/4)
  - "Leading members of the Damrosch orchestra"
    - Print of ink drawing, by unidentified artist, n.d. (Box-folder 27/5)
  - Mannes, Clara Damrosch
    - Pencil sketch (portrait), by unidentified artist, 1889 (Box-folder 27/6)
    - Watercolor (portrait), by Ethelwyn B. Upton, 1891 (Box-folder 27/7)
  - Mannes, Clara and David
    - Wedding announcement with ink drawing and written note, by unidentified artist, 1898 (Box-folder 27/8)
  - Mannes, David
    - Photogravure plates (2 portraits), by unidentified artist, n.d. (Box-folder 33/1-2)
    - Reproduction of drawing (portrait), by Robert Gordon Hardie, 1897 (Box-folder 27/9)
    - Reproduction of pencil sketch (portrait), by unidentified artist, 1910 (Box-folder 27/10)
  - Mannes, Marya
    - Reproduction of oil painting (portrait), by unidentified artist, n.d. (Box-folder 27/11)
  - Mielziner, Jo
    - Pencil sketch (portrait), by unidentified artist, 1920 (Box-folder 27/12)
  - Miscellaneous subjects by Clara Damrosch Mannes
    - Pencil sketches, 1889-1891, n.d. (Box-folder 27/13)
    - Pencil sketches (2 sketch books), 1894 (Box-folder 28/1-2)
  - Miscellaneous subjects by Francesca Duran-Reynals
    - "Retrat de Marya Mannes," 1973 [brochure includes reproduction of portrait] (Box-folder 35/9)
  - Miscellaneous subjects by Helen Damrosch Tee Van
    - Reproduction of pencil sketches (Box-folder 27/14)
  - Miscellaneous subjects by Marya Mannes
    - Juvenilia (Box-folder 27/15)
    - Sculptures (photographic reproductions), n.d. (Box-folder 27/16)
    - Sculptures (album of photographic reproductions), 1936, Florence (Box-folder 28/3)
  - Miscellaneous subjects by Thomas Wood Stevens
    - Watercolor, 1933. Inscribed: To Walter Damrosch - in souvenir (Box-folder 36/3)
  - Miscellaneous subjects by unidentified artists
    - Ink drawings (Box-folder 27/17)
    - Pastel drawings (Box-folder 27/18)
    - Pencil sketches (Box-folder 27/19)
    - Pencil sketches [oversize] (Box-folder 35/10)
    - Pencil sketches with pastels (Box-folder 27/20)
    - Watercolors (Box-folder 27/21)
  - "Victory and defeat," pencil sketch, by Marya Mannes, n.d. (Box-folder 27/22)
- Awards, 1942-69 (Box 29-32, Box 35)
  Awards consist of certificates, diploma, and plaques.
  Arranged alphabetically by recipient, then name of presenter
  - Damrosch, Walter
    - Institute for Education by Radio, Ohio State University, 1942 May 5 [certificate] (Box-folder 35/11)
  - Mannes, Marya
    - American Jewish Congress National Women's Division, 1969 Jan. 20 [plaque] (Box 29)
    - Hollins College Citation, 1968 Feb. 22 (Box-folder 30/1)
    - Long Island University Journalism Department, George Polk Memorial Award, 1958 [plaque] (Box 31)
    - Temple University, Honorary Doctor of Letters, 1976 May 27 [diploma] (Box-folder 30/2)
    - Theta Sigma Phi, National Fraternity for Women in Journalism, Philadelphia Professional Chapter, Award of Honor, 1962 May 16 [plaque] (Box 32)
- Subject File, 1911-61 and undated (Box 7, Box 35)